JR. DATA SCIENTIST

□+90 532 666 97 86 | ▼mustafanayansakk@gmail.com | ☑ MustafaNayansak | 匝 mustafa-nayansak

Summary

I HAVE INTEGRATED THE STATISTICAL KNOWLEDGE AND SKILLS THAT I HAVE LEARNED IN UNDERGRADUATE EDUCATION WITH THE SUBJECTS OF "DATA SCIENCE" AND "BIG DATA". I AM EXPERIENCED IN STATISTICAL DATA ANALYSIS, STATISTICAL LEARNING, DATA MINING TECHNIQUES. I USE R PROGRAMMING LANGUAGE FOR DATA SCIENCE PROCESSES, WRITING DYNAMIC DOCUMENTS (RMARKDOWN), GENERATING USER INTERFACE FOR VISUALIZATION AND ANALYZING (SHINY).

Education

Istanbul Technical University

Istanbul Turkey

MSc in Big Data and Businness Analytics

Sep 2019 - 2020

• I'm going to do a master's degree in Big Data and Business Analytics. With this program I can have the necessary information about Data Science as a course content, I will be able to find solutions to many problems in the field of business.

Dokuz Eylul University

Izmir Turkey

BSc in Statistics | GPA of 3.03/4.00

Sep 2012-2018

- During my undergraduate education, I took many courses that I could improve myself in theoretical and applied statistics, I participated in assignments and project groups, I did a compulsory internship at a production factory, and I worked on a project in a one-year period with a group in the graduation project.
- My "Graduating Project" subject was about developing R package and Shiny web application for "Comparing J Independent Group With a Method Based on Trimmed Means". I presented this work at the 15th Statistics Colloquium organized by Yıldız Technical University.

Work Experience_

Blogger Istanbul Turkey

Veri Bilimi Okulu Nov 2018 - Present

- I am writing a series of articles on Categorical Data Analysis and Shiny Web Applications.
- I am shooting tutorial videos about Shiny Web Applications.
- I attended the Data Science training organized by Cukurova University and VBO as a speaker.

 Internship
 Izmir Turkey

KAEL MÜHANDISLIK ELEKTRONIK SAN.TIC.LTD.ŞTI

Jan 2017 - Feb 2017

• In this factory that produces processors, I made a study on the analysis of errors on the produced processors, the relations between errors, data visualization processes. This process is for me; the importance of reporting the proper use of statistical techniques at every stage of production, accurately and comprehensibly, that a lot of experience and success in business life can only come from quality.

Technical Skills _____

- C#, C++
- Minitab
- Python(Level : Beginner)
- R(Algorithma Knowledge, Creating R Packages, RMarkdown, Shiny Web Applications)
- SPSS, SPSS Modeler
- SQL
- Office(Word, Excel, Access...)
- Wordpress

Voluntary Work Experience

EVS Volunteer Porto Portugal

MEDEsTU Dec 2018 - Jan 2019

• I am worked as a volunteer at the European Voluntary Service in Porto, Portugal. I wrote a KA-102 (Key Action) report in this project. KA-102 is an application form of erasmus+ projects. In addition, I participated in trainings and various cultural activities. I improved my language competences, travelled 4 countries, met many people from all over the World. It was an amazing experience for me.

Volunteer | Izmir Turkey

BIR VARMIŞ BIR YOKMUŞ PROJECT

June 2018

• It was Orienteering competition in İzmir Kültürpark. An Orienteering tournament has been held with groups consisting of a primary school, a high school and a university student. The main purpose of this organization was to make young people more sensitive about the environment and to show the importance of team work by bringing young people of different age groups together.

Volunteer | Izmir Turkey

Abla Abi Kardes Project

Oct 2017 - May 2018

• In a region where middle and low income families are selected by İzmir Municipality, we met of primary school and secondary school students. In this project, which takes 28 weeks, me and my project friend, we go to the chosen their home on Saturdays, We were talking about a theme chosen by project management (e.g. World Disability Day), we encouraged them to be sensitive and good people. Our aim was to give them new perspectives and become role models to them.

Presentations _____

Speaker Apr 2019

CUKUROVA UNIVERSITY

Adana Turkev

In training, I talked about Data Science and Big Data applications in the world, Cloud Technologies and Version Control Systems. You can find
more information about the training at 'https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=r4AsLD-efCI'.

Speaker May 2018

YILDIZ TECHNICAL UNIVERSITY

Istanbul Turkey

My "Graduating Project" subject was about developing R package and Shiny web application for "Comparing J Independent Group With a
Method Based on Trimmed Means". I presented this work at the 15th Statistics Colloquium organized by Yıldız Technical University. You can
find more information about the presentation at 'https://youtu.be/IPeFRcHh8Bc'

Language_

English Nov 2018

IELTS ACADEMIC TEST British Council

• Overall: 5.5 - Level: B2

Personal Skills

- Have enough knowledge on probability and statistics
- Experienced in achieving the right information and integrating it into the subject studied
- Actively use statistical tools for problem analysis
- Recognizing and separating the problem.
- Presentation

Athletic Activities

Caver Nov 2012 - Mar 2014

MEMBER, BOARD OF DIRECTORS

DEU Cave Research Club(DEUMAK)

- I played an active role in organizing more than 40 camp organizations. I had training in cave research, rescue and first aid, mapping and single rope techniques (SRT).
- I took part in decision-making mechanisms such as maintenance of the rope and climbing equipment, transportation, making assigns in the cave and outside the cave, organizing the necessary documents for the organization.



- (1) Prof.Dr. Aylin Alın » aylin.alin@deu.edu.tr
- (2) Yrd.Doç.Dr. Engin Yıldıztepe » engin.yildiztepe@deu.edu.tr
- (3) Doc.Dr. Neslihan Demirel » neslihan.ortabas@deu.edu.tr